Sunnyvale, CA (408) 320-8343 rodwoodman.com

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Front-End Focused Full Stack Developer

Versatile and thorough Web applications developer who loves to produce user-focused dashboard interfaces. Embraces subjectivity but is grounded in full stack development experience. Balances systems-thinking with attention-to-detail to solve whole-product challenges. Open collaborator driven to continually improve UX and demystify design complexity.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- <u>Code</u>: HTML, CSS, SASS, ExtJS, AngularJS, ReactJS, Highcharts, Python, Golang, MongoDB.
- <u>Tools</u>: REST APIs, VSC, Git, Bitbucket, vim, Sublime Text 2, Photoshop, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle.
- Methods: OOP, Continuous Integration, SPA, wikis, UX, user-centered design (UCD), wireframes.
- Soft skills: analytical, communicative, collaborative, iterative, opinionated, grammar-loving.

#### **SAMPLE WEB APPS**

- Boardgameinator: Board game comparisons; ReactJS, Bootstrap, BoardGameGeek.com API;
- ComparingStocks: Meaningful stock allocation data; ReactJS, Alpha Vantage API;
- <u>TrailProfiler</u>: Charts together GPX and JPG files; VueJS, ChartistJS, Bootstrap;

#### **EXPERIENCE**

ARUBA NETWORKS, Santa Clara, CA

2016 - 2020

# Senior Applications Engineer - Support Portal for Aruba Central Guest

- Jointly responsible on a team of 6 for a supportability interface to a Docker AWS NMS application.
- Added a RadSec capture UI, as well as Twilio and SendGrid API integration for troubleshooting.
- Documented and presented the ecosystem architecture over Confluence and Zoom.

# Senior Applications Engineer - Config Sync tool for ClearPass

- Solely responsible for a new tool to audit and sync the configs of 100 ClearPass cluster at once.
- Designed and built the entire UI and internal APIs from informal product requirements.
- Released the major functionality of scheduling, reporting, filtering, exporting, backup and restore.

#### TRUEPATH WIRELESS, San Jose, CA

2015 - 2016

# **NMS** Engineer

- Jointly responsible on a team of 2 for the Network Management System (NMS) product.
- Redesigned the UI for better network insights from the collected telemetry data.
- Sped up the pace of NMS improvements by releasing new code every 2-3 weeks.

CISCO SYSTEMS, San Jose, CA

2005 - 2014

#### **Software Engineer**

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Master of Science in Computer Engineering - Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, CA Bachelor of Science in Electronic Engineering - Cal Poly State University, San Luis Obispo, CA

MEAN Stack Blackbelt - Coding Dojo, San Jose, CA

Web Design Certificate - UCSC Extension Silicon Valley, Santa Clara, CA